How did we end up here?
Birdman or (The Unexpected Virtue of Ignorance) is a drama,
comedy film directed by Alejandro González Iñárritu.
A fading actor best known for his portrayal of a popular superhero
attempts to mount a comeback by appearing in a Broadway play.
As opening night approaches, his attempts to become more altruistic, rebuild his career,
and reconnect with friends and family prove more difficult than expected.
Riggan, played by Michael Keaton.
Sam, played by Emma Stone.
Jake, played by Zach Galifianakis.
Mike, played by Edward Norton.
Laura, played by Andrea Riseborough.
Lesley, played by Naomi Watts.
Birdman, stylized as BİRDMAN or (The Unexpected Virtue of Ignorance), is a 2014 American
satirical surrealist black comedy-drama film directed by Alejandro González Iñárritu.
The film stars Michael Keaton as a washed-up Hollywood actor, best known for playing a superhero named Birdman, and follows the struggles he faces while trying to make
a comeback by writing, directing, and starring in a Broadway adaptation of Raymond Carver's short story "What We Talk About When We Talk About Love".
The film's supporting cast includes Zach Galifianakis, Edward Norton,
Andrea Riseborough, Amy Ryan, Emma Stone, and Naomi Watts.
With a brief exception, Birdman is presented as though it was filmed in one
continuous take, an idea Iñárritu had from the film's conception.
Cinematographer Emmanuel Lubezki believed that the recording time necessary for the
long take approach could not have been made with older technology.
The film was shot in New York City during the spring of 2013 with a budget of $16.5 million, jointly
financed by Fox Searchlight Pictures, Regency Enterprises, and Worldview Entertainment.
It premiered at the 71st Venice International Film Festival in 2014.
Birdman had a limited theatrical release in the United States on
October 17, 2014, followed by a wide release on November 14.
Grossing more than $103 million worldwide, the film received critical acclaim, with praise for its screenplay,
direction, cinematography, and the performances of the cast (particularly Keaton, Norton, and Stone).
It won the Academy Award for Best Picture, along with Best Director, Best Original Screenplay, and Best Cinematography from a total of
nine nominations, tying it with The Grand Budapest Hotel for the most nominated and awarded film at the 87th Academy Awards.
It also won Outstanding Cast in a Motion Picture at the 21st Screen Actors Guild Awards, as well as Best
Actor in a Musical or Comedy for Keaton and Best Screenplay at the 72nd Golden Globe Awards.
The film explores themes of new york city, midlife
crisis, superhero, dark comedy, times square.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and emotional.